Every one of you is aware of the spirited debate that has been raging for
decades between evolutionists and creationists. This hot debate began in
the mid 19th century, about 125 years ago when Charles Darwin developed his theory
of gradual evolution. Basically, what Charles Darwin said was
that life began spontaneously from inanimate inorganic matter.
This beginning of life was supposedly in water and a single simple cell first
formed, then this cell split and multiplied and evolved into new forms of life.
With the passage of millions upon millions of years,
fish came into existence in this water.
And with additional millions upon millions of years, some of the fish
started to walk on land, and started to develop lungs instead of gills.
Eventually, again additional millions and
millions of years were required for some of these land creatures to develop wings
and the ability to fly. Another branch of these land animals continued to develop
and evolve all the way to human beings. Of course, as scientists, we took this
theory of Charles Darwin and we scrutinized it. We put it to the test
like any other theory. Darwin used terms like natural selection, mutations,
survival of the fittest to explain his theory.
Now, during the last 100 years of scientific revolution, we learned quite a few things.
Many of the things that you and I learned as youngsters have been
found to be wrong or at best trivialized. So, we took this theory of evolution and
we studied it carefully. We started to look for the evidence. We treated it like
any other theory, trying to prove it and turn it into a law.
So, in the process of studying the theory and collecting evidence, fossils and skeletal remnants,
and so on, and the other sciences combined to teach us that parts of the
original theory of Darwin were unworkable or scientifically wrong, just downright wrong.
And this led to the modification of Darwin's theory.
As scientists, we had to modify the original theory of evolution as written
by Charles Darwin in order to fit the new established facts.
Let me give you a couple of examples. Gradual evolution proved to be wrong. Our
fossil record does not support gradual evolution. You heard about the missing
link. Every one of you knows about the missing link. And I'm here to tell you
that there is not just a missing link. There are thousands of missing links and
to solve this problem, the scientists came up with a new theory called
punctuated equilibrium. Stephen Gould of Harvard and Niles Eldredge came up
with this idea, punctuated equilibria, to solve the problem of the missing links.
What they said was that evolution happened in giant leaps, not gradually.
So, this was the first major modification of the original theory of evolution.
Another idea, for example, that we had to abandon was Lamarck's concept of inherited -
let me give you the correct expression here - the transmission of acquired
characteristics. This concept of Lamarck had to be abandoned because it proved
unworkable. And to give you an example from everyday life,
Lamarck for example said that the giraffe has a long neck because those
animals had to reach for high leaves and they lived in an area where they needed
the long neck. Well, this was proven unworkable and scientifically untenable
and it was eventually abandoned. So, we kept adjusting and
modifying the theory of evolution. What I wish to share with you today is a
scientific examination of both evolution and creation.
I will present to you physical evidence, irrefutable, incontrovertible evidence that will help
you decide exactly what took place: evolution and/or creation.
The title of this program is Evolution or Creation: the Final Argument. And hopefully, by the
end of this program, you will see enough evidence to help you
make a final decision about evolution and creation.
We will find out exactly what components of Darwin's theory are correct and which components are wrong.
And I must point out at this time that Darwin was indeed a genius when he
suggested natural selection, survival of the fittest, and mutations to explain his theory.
Let me give you a good example. The navel orange, this beautiful fruit is a
new creature. That's right. Your great grandfather never saw or tasted a navel orange.
And this happened through mutation. All of a sudden this tree came
out with this beautiful fruit, seedless and delicious. And, of course, now it is
spread all over the world. We take it for granted, but this is a good example of evolution.
However, I must point out that the navel orange evolved from oranges.
In other words, we did not see an apple evolve from oranges or a fig.
An orange, it is still... the navel orange is still an orange. And this is an important point.
The evolution creation issue is before the Supreme Court this year in 1987.
So, this program is quite timely because right now, we have a
powerful scientific and objective tool that can tell us exactly which events in
the world are probable and which events are not probable.
This powerful objective and scientific tool is mathematics.
Mathematics is the most scientific of all Sciences. It is a pure science and through mathematics, we
can tell if a bridge or a building is going to collapse or not under any given
circumstances. So, we can use this powerful tool to examine both evolution
and creation. This is exactly what we're going to do together and hopefully by
the end of this program, we, you and I, will reach a final decision.
So the name, the Final Argument, is quite appropriate.
Let me first simplify the mathematical laws, the laws of probability that we
will be using today to examine both evolution and creation.
Let us say we have five cubes, each cube is labeled with only one number, either one or two
or three or four or five. If we mix these five cubes in a mixer and have them
fall down in some kind of a device so they'll be lined up in one line or toss
them up in the air and have them fall in such a way so they'll be lined up,
what are the possible combinations of these five cubes?
How many permutations are we going to have? Well, the laws of mathematics are
very simple. They tell you that you will get 120 combinations and you obtain this
by multiplying, multiplying 1 by 2 by 3 by 4 by 5. The product is 120.
So, you will get 120 combinations or permutations. In other words, every combination, let us say
if they fall down lined up 1 2 3 4 5 in this particular combination, this
combination has a chance out of 120 chances. Let me show you on the board.
Here we are with the 5 cubes, each one labeled with only one number.
You toss them up in the air and have them fall down so they'll be lined up in this
particular combination. What are the possible combinations, how many?
Here, we see the formula, the number of possible combinations of permutations is 1 times
2 times 3 times 4 times 5 or 120 combinations.
The probability for any specific combination is obtained by dividing one
over 120, because each combination has a chance out of 120 chances.
And 1 over 120 equals 0.0086. This probability diminishes fast as we increase the
number of cubes. For example, if we increase the number of cubes by 1, so you
have six cubes instead of five, the number of possible combination jumps
from 120 to 720 - 1 times 2 times 3 times 4 times 5 times 6.
And the probability for any specific combination goes down from one out of 120 to one out of 720,
or 0.0014. So, you can see how fast it diminishes.
Okay, well, when will the probability diminish all the way to zero?
Well, mathematicians who are exceedingly precise, conservative, and careful scientists
decided that if you have 84 cubes, then the probability is zero for
getting any specific combinations. What does this mean?
Let me go to the board and show you this.
I have the number here for 84 cubes. The probability, look at this, is zero point
zero zero zero zero zero zero zero zero all the way 50 zeroes and then 208.
So, you can see here that the probability for all practical purposes is zero.
And this by the way is extending it the full benefit of the doubt.
What does this mean in practical terms? This means that you can take these
eighty four cubes toss them up in the air and have them fall in such a way
so they line up, and if you want the specific combination of one two three
four five six seven eight all the way to 84, if you want this specific combination,
you can toss up these cubes and have them fall down lined up forever and you
will never see this combination. This is what probability 0 means. You can appreciate that.
Now, many of you are familiar with the lottery. You know what
your chances are of winning the lottery. And here in the lottery, we're talking
about five or six numbers. So, you can really appreciate the improbability of
having 84 cubes line up in a specific combination.
To make a long story short, the genetic material of the human being, the gene
that decides what kind of creature we have, this genetic material contains,
listen to this, 30 billion nucleotides arranged in specific sequences and specific quantities.
Now, what are the probabilities of arranging these
billions of nucleotides in a specific sequence? Of course, you know the answer
from mathematical laws. The probability is 0 many times over.
We are talking here about, not 84 numbers or 8,400 numbers or 84,000 or 84 million numbers,
we are talking about 30 billion nucleotides.
Now as scientists, we have been talking about similarities between the human
being and the ape as far as genetic material is concerned. And you know
something, if we have 90 percent similarity, we are still talking about
300 million nucleotides that must be arranged in a specific sequence
and specific quantities to change the ape into a human being.
Even if we have 99% similarity, we are still talking about 30 million
nucleotides that must be haphazardly arranged in specific sequence in order
to change the ape into a human being. And you know that the probability for
this is zero. We have now these mathematical laws that can tell us
exactly which event is probable and which event is not probable. And we know
that the probability that 30 million nucleotides, in case of 99% similarity
between the human and the ape, we know that this probability is zero.
We're not talking about 84 numbers. We're talking about 30 million nucleotides.
Another thing, at the other end of the evolutionary spectrum, we're talking
about the so called simple cell. You remember, when I stated Charles Darwin's
theory. Darwin said that first a simple single cell was formed. Well, the cell
that Darwin is talking about is not simple at all. It's a very complex chemical factory.
In fact, it is the most complex chemical factory we know of. It has
hundreds of actions and reactions going on in the cell and it has the DNA
material that is very complex. And just to quote something that will
make you smile at least. About 50 years ago,
(H. G.) Wells, (Julian) Huxley, and (G. P.) Wells wrote in their text: the Science of Life, I'm quoting now.
Nothing can be seen inside the nucleus of the cell but the clear fluid.
Now, those great scientists knew nothing about DNA.
In the last 50 years, there was so much advancement in science that we realize
now how many actions and reactions are going on within the nucleus.
We know about the DNA, the helical structure. And we know the arrangement and the
specificity of sequences of nucleotides. And we know now that haphazard
creation of a simple cell, as Darwin called it, is not...the probability is zero.
According to Darwin, the evolution of organs paralleled the evolution of the organisms.
For example, the eye, this very complex organ started out, according to Darwin, as a
light-sensitive spot on the surface. After millions upon millions of years,
this light sensitive spot became a depression. Additional millions upon
millions of years passed and the depression became a pit and then
millions more years caused a lens to develop in that depression.
Well, according to this scenario, creatures existed for millions upon
millions of years in total blindness, awaiting the evolution of the 20/20 vision,
the evolution of the eye. And this, of
course, to you and to me doesn't... logically does not make sense.
And now we see by mathematical laws that the probability is zero that this happened haphazardly.
Do you know how many things are in the eye? The lens, the cornea, the
retina, there is... I can give you a list two pages of components of the eye.
Each one of them cannot be haphazardly, haphazardly formed. We have now these laws
of mathematics telling us that the probability is zero.
Let me give you some examples. The dragonfly has 30,000 lens in each eye,
lenses in each eye, 30,000 of them. Now, for millions of years, the dragonfly
existed with 30,000 lenses in each eye. What kind of intelligence told the
dragonfly to stop evolving at 30,000? Imagine the little area of the small eye of
the dragonfly divided into 30,000 cones, and each cone is fitted with a perfectly
shaped lens, imagine that. Now, why did the dragonfly
stop at 30,000? Why not a couple hundred more, or a couple thousand more? Who told
the dragonfly that this is enough evolution for your eye?
How about the housefly? 4000 lenses in each eye. The housefly has 4000 lenses in each eye.
Now, what kind of intelligence told the housefly to stop evolving the eye at 4000 lenses?
For millions of years, the fly had 4,000
lenses in each eye. Now, who told it to stop evolving? Why not go on to 5000 lenses?
The honeybee has 6,300 lenses in each
eye. And again, we test the same question. And if you pursue that question, it will
prove the existence of a Super Intelligent Being that told these
organisms to stop evolving their eyes at a certain number of lenses. So, this is the irony of it.
So, while evolution is proven to be correct by scientific
research, the initiation of life or the origin of species is proven to be not
probable. The probability is zero and therefore it had to be created by a
Super Intelligent Creator. And we will discuss this matter and see the
mathematical evidence supporting it before the end of this program.
Let us look at some established facts that you and I have witnessed in the
last few years. The first fact is that despite our tremendous scientific
advances, these great achievements, not a single scientist, not a single
researcher, not a single laboratory has succeeded in initiating life from
inorganic inanimate matter. They utterly failed in duplicating Charles Darwin's
basic concept that life evolved from inanimate inorganic matter.
What the scientists, what we succeeded in doing was to synthesize amino acids
and proteins from oxygen, hydrogen, nitrogen, and so on. This is the extent of
our success in the lab. We could not produce life.
Now, of course, it is natural that we can make amino acids or proteins from oxygen,
hydrogen, nitrogen, and so on. After all these are the ingredients that make up
amino acids and proteins. It's no big deal that you create the circumstances
for the ingredients to link up together and make up these chemicals. But these
are dead chemicals, dead molecules of amino acids and protein. And some people
would say these are the building blocks of life. Well, that is right. These are the
building blocks but this is the extent of it, just that, building blocks.
Now, if you take a bunch of building blocks, put them in the corner and leave them there
for thousands of years, will they assemble themselves into a building, with the deliberate design?
Of course not. So, as scientists, we succeeded in creating
the building blocks, but we could not create the building. This is a very important fact.
The debate between evolutionists and creationists was so hot and so emotional
that some of my fellow scientists gave up their scientific objectivity. And I find
myself forced to criticize fellow scientists for behaving like unscientific creationists.
Let me give you a good example, has to do with the
booklet published by the National Academy of Sciences back in 1983.
In that booklet, they published a picture, one of their favorite pictures, the skulls of
a number of hominids. And they concluded from that picture that the skull of the
more advanced hominid evolved from the more primitive skull,
that the advanced skull evolved from the primitive skull.
Well, this is a perfectly valid and scientific conclusion. There's no problem with that.
But the problem is that the Academy ignored an equally valid conclusion
that these skulls, the animals that possessed these or the creatures that
possessed these skulls, simply existed independently, independent of each other
without any relationship whatsoever. Now, scientific objectivity dictates that
we present both views, that the skulls evolved from each other and/or the
skulls existed independently of each other.
This kind of abandoning scientific objectivity resulted from the high
emotionalism and fanaticism on both sides of the evolution creation issue.
But scientists would never abandon their objectivity. We'll be in deep trouble
if we abandon our objectivity. Note we cannot say evolution is a fact and
it is up to the rest of the world to prove otherwise. This is putting the cart
before the horse. When we say that this evolution business is a theory,
we are...the burden of proof is on us to provide the evidence that evolution is a fact.
It is our duty to establish evolution as a truth, not the other way around.
To summarize, we all appreciate the power of mathematics as a pure science, the
most scientific of all sciences. And we are all familiar with the simple formula
of Einstein, E=MC squared. And we are familiar with the tremendous
consequences of such a simple formula. Mathematics is an objective and powerful
tool that can tell us exactly what events in the world are probable
and what events are not probable. We have been talking about a DNA, the genes,
30 billion nucleotides in the human gene that interact with other life processes.
We are not talking about a toy. You know, when you go to the toy store and buy a
bunny rabbit, for example, it has ears and realistic eyes but these eyes don't see.
And this toy rabbit doesn't have any cells or DNA or nucleotides that are
arranged or any life actions and reactions. We are, we are assuming here
that we are just talking about the simple arrangement of nucleotides in
specific sequences and specific quantities. We are talking about just
physical arrangement. The probability is... this infinitesimally small probability
is multiplied by other infinitesimally small probabilities when you interact
the nucleotides, the DNA with other life processes in the cell and throughout the organism.
Now, we can use the same powerful tool to prove the alternative, namely creation.
Now, how in the world can anybody prove
creation? Nobody could imagine anything that can prove creation. But you know
something, about hundred years ago, we could not envision TV or the telephone
or communication satellite, but here we are. If you can see your
great-grandfather today and describe the television to him, he would disagree with you,
he would think you went crazy. So, similarly we could not imagine anything
that will prove or disprove creation but how about a coded message from outer space?
Did you ever think about that? A coded
message from outer space, telling you I am the Creator and this is how I did.
A message that will give you all the details.
Many of you are familiar with the Carl Sagan's latest novel called Contact.
In Contact, he presented a fictitious story about a coded message from outer space
from some intelligent life out there. And the message was decoded by computers and
so on. And you know something, this is not fictitious at all. I am here to tell you
that we actually received a coded message, mathematically coded message
from the Super Intelligent Creator, telling us exactly what happened,
how the universe and the six million living organisms, six million species of
living organisms in this universe, how they all came to be.
Now that we possess this irrefutable mathematical proof that came from outer
space, from the Super Intelligent Creator, We can look back and at least smile at
statements of even some of the leading creationists. Let me quote for you one of
those leading creationists, Duane Gish. He said it is impossible to conceive an
experiment that could disprove the possibility of creation. Creation thus
does not fulfill the criteria of a scientific theory. So,
even the creationists gave up thinking that there could never be anything to
prove or disprove creation. But here we are just like any other discovery, we
find this mathematically coded message from the Super Intelligent Creator.
The first hint of the mathematical code was reported about 900 years ago by a Jewish
rabbi, Rabbi Judah the pious. And by the way, I'm talking here about
unaltered original untranslated scripture. This is very important, very
crucial because there have been many distortions and changes, alterations, losses,
additions to the scriptures and we have to be extremely careful to know that we
are dealing with original unaltered untranslated scriptures, literally the
very same words that the Creator wrote down or sent to us. So, what Rabbi Judah
found... well, let me quote for you. It is easier this way.
The people... now, this is... this quotation is from a book called studies in Jewish Mysticism.
It was edited by Joseph Dan and Frank Talmage, and here is what they said.
The people, Jews, in France made it a custom
to add in the morning prayer the words ashrei temimei derekh” blessed are those
who walk the righteous way. And our Rabbi the Pious of blessed memory wrote that
they were completely and utterly wrong. It is all gross falsehood because there
are only 19 times - now pay attention to these numbers - there are only 19 times
that the holy name is mentioned in that portion of the morning prayer
and similarly you find the world Elohim 19 times
in the pericope of Ve-‘elleh shemot. Similarly, you find that Israel is called
sons 19 times and there are many other examples. All these sets of 19 are
intricately intertwined and they contain many secrets and esoteric meanings.
So, this was the first hint of a mathematical composition
in the message that came to us from the Creator, or some kind of a code.
Now, you realize now that it is important to find
original scripture, unchanged. And just like the evolutionists looking for
fossils and skeletal remains, scientists have been looking the world over for
original scriptures. You heard about the Dead Sea Scrolls and all the finds in
lots of... in the Middle East in many places. All these are attempts. Some of
them are failures and some of them are successes.
So, I set out to find an original scripture, and here is the result.
In this whole world, there's only one scripture that was never altered, not a single letter
was changed in that scripture, and that scripture is the Quran.
So, what I did was I got the Quran, an original copy, with the original Arabic and I put it in
the computer and I decoded an intricate mathematical code that is clearly beyond human ability.
So, now we have physical proof using the ultimate in scientific
evidence, mathematics, telling us that everything that happened.
That there is a Super Intelligent Creator. And in that message, we see how we came into being,
why we are here, where we are going, and many many other answers to lots of our
most urgent questions.
Before I put the Quran in the computer, I noticed a unique phenomenon that you
will never find in any other literary work. I noticed, for example, that chapter
2 of the Quran has in the first verse... there are only three letters in the first verse.
That's it. A. L. M., that is verse 1 of chapter 2. And these letters remained
mysterious for 1,400 years. Scholars and scientists of all kind have been looking
at these initials A L M and the other initials in Quran trying to figure
out what they mean and they could not do it. The computer did it recently and
to give you an idea, if you count the letters A L and M in chapter 2 of Quran,
you'll find that the total is 9899. And this number, 9899, is a multiple of 19.
Remember the work of Rabbi Judah the Pious? The number 19 turns out to be
the common denominator in the older scripture and in the newer scripture.
19 is the common denominator in the Bible, the original unaltered Bible, and also in
the latest edition of the scripture, the Quran. And this is very important.
Now, there are 29 chapters in Quran, covering half the Quran. The Quran has 114
chapters. Some of them are longer and some are shorter but the 29 initialed
chapters constitute half the Quran. And this mathematical system goes from
the very simple to the very complex. So, it is suitable for people of all levels of education.
For example, chapter 50 is entitled Q. That's it, just one letter, Q.
And it is initialed with the letter Q. The computer said that this chapter contains
57 Q's. When you count them, you can count them if you know the Arabic letters.
And you'll find that the total is 57, 19x3. There is one other chapter in
Quran that is initiated with the letter Q and that is chapter 42 which happens
to be more than twice as long as chapter 50, entitled Q. And when you count
the letter Q in chapter 42, you'll find exactly the same number, 57. So, the only
two Q-initialed chapters have the same number of Q's, 57 and 57.
Chapter 68 is initialed with the letter N as in Nancy, N. And you count the letters N in this
chapter and you come up with 133, 19x7. And this goes on and on and it gets
more and more complex until you realize that this is not human fabrication, that
this is way beyond human ability. For example, we have 7 chapters in Quran
that we see initialed with the letters H M, 7 of them about 1/10. They constitute about 1/10 of the whole book.
And when you count the letters H, HA and the M, MEEM
in these 7 chapters, you come up with a total 2147 and this is a multiple of 19,
the common denominator throughout the scriptures, the coded message from the Creator to us.
2147. Now, if only one letter H or one letter M was lost or added in the last
1400 years, you will end up with 2,148, for example, and this is not a multiple
of 19. The whole system collapses. Or 2146, because mathematics is a pure science.
It is the most sensitive scale. And if you lose one number, you don't have a multiple of 19.
By the time the computer was done with the mathematical analysis of Quran,
a vast mathematical code emerged. And you could see that every letter, every word
in Quran is precisely calculated beyond human ability and you will be
absolutely convinced that this is a message from a Super Intelligent Creator,
telling us exactly what happened. Let me give you another good example
because some people may think that only the initialed chapters are mathematically composed.
This simple example is that the opening statement in Quran consists of
four words, and the number of letters in this
statement is 19. It's a very important statement. It says in the name of God, the
Gracious, the Merciful and it is considered the most important statement
in Quran. It consists of 19 letters and every word is found in the whole book
in multiples of 19. For example, the first word ISM, or name, is mentioned
exactly 19 times throughout the whole book. The second word is God, ALLAH, and it
is found 2698 times. This is 19x142.
The third word the gracious, in Arabic AL-RAHMAN, is mentioned in the whole book 57, 19x3,
And the last word AL-RAHIM, or the Merciful, is mentioned 114 times or 19x6.
Now, right there, you can appreciate that this cannot
happen in a human fabricated book, in a human-made book because you can go to
the library, if you go to the library and examine 1 million human-made
books, how many books would you find where the opening statement consists of
an X number of letters and every word in the opening statement is repeated in the
whole book in multiples of X? How many? Again, the laws of probability say zero.
You will not find a book where all the words of the opening statement comply
with this criterion. So, there you have it a very simple...this very simple phenomenon
by the way was published in Scientific American in the September 1981 issue.
And the comment on it was that this is an ingenious study of the Quran. I was really flattered.
What does this have to do with the evolution creation issue?
Well, we have here a vitally important document from the Super Intelligent Creator telling us
in words and letters that are mathematically composed beyond human
intelligence, telling us exactly what happened. And in this document, we see
that life began in water, just like Darwin said. So, this portion of Darwin's
theory is confirmed. We also see evolution and changes in creation in
Quran chapter 35 verse 1, and in chapter 16 verse 8. We see that evolution is a
continual process. So, according to this vitally important document, evolution is
a divinely guided process. Evolution is a creation of the Super Intelligent
Creator and it is something that is happening now on continuous basis. We
learn that every one of us was individually created and the evolution
that is taking place is individually controlled and guided by the Super
Intelligent Creator. One of the most exciting things about
this document is that the dichotomy, the great rift between science and religion
is eliminated. We now see this document from the Super Intelligent Creator
telling us that evolution is the Creator's work and that it is going on
continuously and therefore there is no need for this dichotomy between science and religion.
So, what we see here is mathematical,
irrefutable evidence that creation and evolution, both, are correct and they
complement each other. Of course, we have to examine the existing theories of
evolution and creation, and correct them in view of the new statements that came
to us from the Super Intelligent Creator. While on the subject of confirming or
rejecting existing Scriptures, I must point out that this mathematically
composed document from the Super Intelligent Creator, the Quran, sets the
record straight as far as many existing creationist
ideas are concerned. For example, we learn that the earth is billions of
years old, not 5000 or 10,000 years old. And we learn that the earth is
egg-shaped as I mentioned before, not flat. And we learn that Noah's Ark, for
example, did not look like what we see in the pictures of Bible stories and so on.
Noah's Ark was simply a raft made of logs tied together with primitive
ropes and Noah did not carry all the animals of the earth on his ark either
or this raft. He carried his domesticated animals to save himself, his family and
his animals from the flood. And the flood did not cover the whole world as we hear
as youngsters. The flood was a local flood. All this is proven by
mathematically composed statements from the Creator Himself.
It is very important to realize that the prevalent creationism has nothing to do
with the original untranslated Bible. That's right. The prevalent creationism
is a product of medieval storytellers and ignorant interpretations and
mistranslations of the original Bible. For example, the Bible says clearly
that one of our days is the same as one thousand years of your Lord. So... or the
day is equal to fifty thousand years if you look at the Quran in chapter 70 verse 4.
So, we are told clearly that the day of our Earth is not equal to any other day.
When you go to the Moon, the day equals 14 Earthly days. If you go to
Mercury, for example, the day over there is 88 of our days. So, the minute you
leave this tiny planet Earth, the day is no longer 24 hours. So, the truth is the
Bible does not say that the earth is 6,000 or 10,000 years old. The Bible does
not say that Noah's flood covered the whole world and the original Bible did
not say that Noah carried all his animals on the ark and the ark did not
look like an aircraft carrier either. These misrepresentations of the Bible
actually give Christianity and religion in general a bad name.
Most people who are pushing the prevalent false creationism are doing a terrible
disservice to Christianity and to the Bible because these misrepresentations
are not the truth. Scientific findings and now mathematics support the truth
in the Bible. And we must remember that the creationism that is prevalent today is
false. The true Christian creationism agrees 100% with science.
It is the prevalence of these ideas that are completely rejected by science and
the scientific findings and established facts. These ideas caused Darwin's
disillusionment with religion. And let me quote for you what Darwin said as a
result of these prevalent creationist ideas. I'm quoting now
I gradually came to disbelieve in Christianity as a divine
revelation. This disbelief crept over me at a very slow rate but at last was complete.
And we cannot blame Darwin for seeing that the earth is billions of
years old as established by science while the creationist ideas say that the
earth is 6,000 years old. You cannot blame the man for not believing that Noah
carried all animals, the lions, the giraffes, the polar bears, and the giant
worms of Australia on on his ark. And you cannot blame Darwin for not believing
that the flood of Noah covered the whole world. So, all these things are now set straight.
We learn from this document that the Quran complements the old
Scriptures and confirms the majority of the truth in those scriptures and
consummates the whole message from the Creator to us.
To conclude, we now possess physical incontrovertible evidence that every one
of the six million species of living organisms came into being through a
creation process. Then, evolution took place and is going on continuously as a
divinely guided and controlled process. Thank you very much.
We have invited into our studio professor Jeff Clark. He is with Arizona
State University. He's an anthropologist and he maintains that creationism isn't
a science and therefore doesn't belong in scientific classes.
On the other hand, we have Dr. Rashad Khalifa. He is a biochemist and, of course, he takes the
opposite stand. And again, we're going to throw our phones open for your opinions
about it. It's a hot issue. It's going to be one that is you're gonna be
viewed with a great deal of interest by the people in United States in
various states. And we're going to find out how this thing is going to evolve.
Well, Bob I have to make a correction here in that I will approach the matter
from a scientific point of view. I agree with most of the things that Jeff
just mentioned in that science is our means to ascertain what the truth is. And we
have a very powerful tool, objective and scientific tool to ascertain what events
in the world are probable and what events are not probable. And this
powerful tool is mathematics. Mathematics is the most powerful, the most scientific
of all sciences and it represents the ultimate in scientific proof.
I realize that nobody can ever imagine a proof that will prove
either evolution or creation, but there is something new and very exciting
and I'm here to present it to you. So, in essence, we are talking about
a mathematically coded message from outer space. If you read the
Carl Sagan's Contact, he's talking about a novel, a fictitious message from outer space.
Now, this is not fiction anymore. And this is what I have come here with.
You're gonna have to put that in your pipe and smoke it.
Sorry. yeah, I dare say. But so far is the particular aspect of the Old Testament
that's of issue here, i.e., the book of Genesis. It's an origin myth like any
other origin myth. It's not a greater nor lesser than...
You keep going back to the book of Genesis, there exists...
The reason I say that is I believe that that underlies scientific creationism as espoused by Henry Morris.
Now, it's obvious Dr. Khalifa does not agree with Dr. Morris as to what...
He's not here right now. I am debating with you. That's quite true but who has written the text
on scientific creationism? Henry Morris. And who is the founder of the Institute for Creation Research?
Henry Morris. How long ago was that?
Well, he goes back about 20 years... Well, we're talking about now, Jeff. As soon as this program
is over, I will show you irrefutable mathematical evidence that we have a document
from outer space from the Creator telling us exactly... How are you gonna prove that
in the Supreme Court for heavens sake? Absolutely, I'll prove it in any court.
All right, I have to take some calls. This is really getting interesting, messages from outer space.
Absolutely. ...to absolutely prove the creation is a fact.
Yes sir. Is it possible that there is some sort of gigantic
protoplasm somewhere out in the cosmos with all the ingredients and all of this energy that
can in fact create things. I'm not talking about an old man in a robe with a beard
and pearly gates and things like that. I'm talking about is there a
possibility with our limited knowledge to envision some sort of humongous thing
that thinks that can create things? You can envision anything that you want
and they are obviously not in the strict rigorous sense, but...
You're not saying this about God. Oh yes, gods are the servants of the societies and the
cultures that create them. They have no existence apart from the societies that...
Even if it is proven to you? Well, I'd like to see somebody prove it.
I'm glad you like to see it because I can show it to you. Bob, there is no escape now that there is a
Super Intelligent out there, either through the theory of evolution, ironically,
or the theory of creation.